# 🌿 EcoTrack

EcoTrack is a lightweight sustainability dashboard that helps users track and visualize environmental data such as electricity usage, carbon emissions, and recycling efforts. It includes a stylish frontend, simple authentication system, and MongoDB-based backend to store user data securely.

---

## 🧰 Key Features

- 🔐 User registration and login system
- 📝 Input forms for sustainability metrics
- 📊 View recorded data in a clean dashboard table
- 🌍 Responsive UI built with plain HTML, CSS, and JavaScript
- 💾 Backend built with Express.js and MongoDB

---

## 🗂️ How to Run the Project from a ZIP File

If you're using a zip file instead of cloning from GitHub, follow these steps:

### ✅ 1. Extract the ZIP
- Right-click on the `.zip` file → "Extract All"
- Open the extracted folder

### ✅ 2. Install Node.js
- Download and install Node.js from: https://nodejs.org
- After installation, open a terminal/command prompt and run:

  ```bash
  node -v

 ## 3.Install Project Dependencies
       npm install

 ## 4.Set Up MongoDB

 ## 5. cd backend
          Start the Server
             node server.js
